<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphics on SNR R User Group</title>
    <link>/tags/graphics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphics on SNR R User Group</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/graphics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphing themes and facets</title>
      <link>/post/2016-10-05-themes_facets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-10-05-themes_facets/</guid>
      <description>Themes One of my favorite aspects of ggplot2 is the use of themes. Not including a theme, the default ggplots theme is the theme_grey which has a dark grey background with white grid lines. See the example below
library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ──────────────────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 3.0.0 ✔ purrr 0.2.5 ## ✔ tibble 1.4.2 ✔ dplyr 0.7.6 ## ✔ tidyr 0.8.1 ✔ stringr 1.3.1 ## ✔ readr 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Graphics</title>
      <link>/post/2016-10-04-webgraphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-10-04-webgraphics/</guid>
      <description>var lodash = _.noConflict();  Plots for the web There has been increasing need and desirability to produce interactive graphics online. News outlets, like the The Economist, New York Times, Vox, 538, Pew, and Quartz, routinely use interactive displays.
There are two packages (among several) that allow us to create interactive graphics. The first is ggivis, which is based on ggplot2 and the other is googlevis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting</title>
      <link>/post/2016-09-30-basicplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-09-30-basicplots/</guid>
      <description>Basic plotting in ggplot ggplot is a package that has truly upped the level of producing quality graphics using R. The “g g” in ggplot refers to the grammar of graphics. There has been a lot of development of the theory in what makes a good plot and I encourage you to read more on the subject.
From the ggplot2 website
 ggplot2 is a plotting system for R, based on the grammar of graphics, which tries to take the good parts of base and lattice graphics and none of the bad parts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>